Yosef Cohen

Chicago, IL | yosef.d.cohen@gmail.com | 773-320-6464 | github.com/ycohen26 | linkedin.com/in/yosef-cohen

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am a web developer with a BA in psychology. I was drawn to psychology because I love knowing how things work, people included. Over the years I have managed group homes for individuals with special needs, worked for a booming tech company on the data-gathering side, and currently work in the financial department of a long-term healthcare provider. No matter the job, I'm all about learning and delving into the industry, learning the ins and outs and all the processes involved.

SKILLS

Technical: Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, Vue.js, React.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, MSSQL, Git, Testing, Pair-Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, APIs, Bootstrap, Word, Excel, Power Point, Crimson, Mac OS, iOS, Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn, and Google

Additional: Hebrew (fluent)

EXPERIENCE

Actualize | January 2019 - Present

Web Developer

- **CycloShop:** Personally built an app which allows users to sell and/or purchase pre-owned bicycles with peace of mind. Gone are the days of virtual garage sales. All transactions, including deposits prior to meeting and trying the bike, are through the app. Buyers can read feedback and ratings from other users on the bike under consideration. Built on a Ruby-on-Rails backend and a Vue.js frontend, incorporating and modifying Bootstrap elements and JavaScript transition elements.
- **Bootcamp:** Learned fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and how to effectively self-teach new technologies
 - Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
 - o Built and tested the backend, incorporating external APIs
 - Created pages and routing, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styled results, incorporated libraries and themes

Intellect Service Consulting Company | Junior SQL Developer | July 2017 - Present

- Aided in providing clients with consulting needs for short to mid-range projects
- Optimized guery performance and populated test data
- Designed, developed, tested and implemented relational databases and procedural database code

Aperion Care | AR Bookkeeper and Biller | January 2019 - Present

- Accounted for 5 10 million dollars in revenue a month
- Collaborated with facility and regional financial coordinators to insure successful collections
- Aided with the maintenance of residents' trust fund accounts
- Produced monthly financial reports
- Corresponded with multiple vendors in a timely manner to guarantee payments due
- Audited resident accounts to ensure residents paid correct amounts per state standards

ConstructConnect | Senior Content Specialist | 2013 – 2019, 2010 – 2011

- Produced accurate and current information to assist subscribers in finding job opportunities
- Managed and updated thousands of companies' profiles
- Trained and onboarded 10 new team members
- Built and maintained professional relationships with sources
- Achieved and exceeded daily and monthly goals to create user-facing content

Libenu Foundation/Clearbrook | Qualified Intellectual Disabilities Professional | 2011 – 2013

- Managed group home for 6 individuals with special needs
- Budgeted home and client expenses and produced expense reports
- Detected and resolved employee payroll discrepancies
- Ensured client medications, facility, and files met state and company standards
- Formulated Individualized Service Plan for each client
- Communicated with client day programs to insure seamless care
- Obtained state required DSP and QIDP certification

Other: Kesher Stam Inc. | 2008 - 2009

EDUCATION

Yeshiva University, New York, NY Bachelor of Arts in Psychology | 2008

- Mazer Yeshiva Program Joseph and Lena Hoening Memorial Award for Excellence in Talmud, 2008
- Two-years abroad in Netiv Aryeh 2003-2005